自由
Freedom.
你不再是奴隶教练
No longer shall you be my Doctore.
你将成为角斗士训练师
You will assume the mantle of lanista…
并可使用你的真名 奥诺玛默斯
and be warmly greeted by your name Oenemaus.
缘何叛乱
What is this madness?!
斯巴达克斯为我等指明道路
Spartacus shows us the way.
他说在其中一个死人的身上发现了你的名字
He sends word to me that one of the fallen bore your name,
就刻在那家伙胸前
carved into his chest.
执政官一个手势 就可以派你去卡普亚
The Consuls will present a motion dispatching you to Capua.
那里有宅子和农场 离城市很远
There are villas and farms, far from the city.
妮维雅被转手多次
Naevia was handed from dominus to dominus.
我们往南走 去找妮维雅
We move south. To find Naevia.
她是巴蒂塔斯的妻子吗
This is Batiatus' wife?
模样相似的幽灵罢了
A shadow of the same.
那她还活着
And yet she lives.
人们看到这个女人
It would give the city hope…
从斯巴达克斯等人手下生还
to see a woman survive…
就能重获希望
Spartacus and his men.
你要去哪儿
Where do you go?
对于失去荣誉的野兽来说
There is but one place…
只有一个地方可去
for an animal without honor.
《斯巴达克斯：复仇》
《一隅》
那可不是小男孩 是可怕的恶魔
That is no boy, but fucking demon.
刚从炼狱里面生出来呢
Belched from the cunt of the underworld.
您来到地下角斗场 真是莫大的惊喜
Your presence in the pits comes as welcome surprise.
泰塔斯·巴蒂塔斯大驾光临的消息一传开
When word that Titus Batiatus graced us with his presence…
你在哪儿发现他的
Where did you find him?
跟那批努米底亚人一起从梅洛克手里买来的
He's with a pack of Numidians purchased from Maalok.
其他人都没活过这周
The others fell within the week.
他脑子不好使 才没跟着他们一起死
This one proves too dim to sniff out their trail.
他受过训练吗
Has he any training?
训练 连疯狗都比他招人喜欢
Training? A rabid dog would be a more agreeable pupil.
叫他名字都不一定能答应
Barely answers to the name given him.
无论多桀骜不驯的人都能被驯服
All men can be tamed no matter how wild.
只要在他心底找到一簇火苗
One must only find an ember of purpose,
再吹风浇油
and give it breath.
火苗有什么意思
I give no shit to embers.
只有钱能让我暖和
Coin warms my breast.
你想要个什么价钱
And the price to see you so inflamed?
十个第纳尔 他就归你了
Ten denarii and the boy is yours.
要训练 要操
To train, to fuck…
随便你怎样
whatever you would have of him.
我只出八个
Eight.
八个 您这么有身份的人
Eight? You appear as honorable man,
还挺喜欢玩菊花嘛
yet attempt to slip cock in ass.
如果我真有这兴趣
If I held such desire,
非把你操成两半不可
you would be split in two.
那就这么定了 以后要多照顾我生意
I give you this bargain, only to entice further purchases.
起来 见过新主人 奥诺玛默斯
Rise. Greet your new master, Oenomaus.
时候到了
It is time.
这帮畜生
Filthy animals.
原来在城下的臭水沟里藏身
Living in offal and shit beneath the city.
要是早知道他们藏在那儿
If we'd known they were there,
我们现在已经带着
we would be riding towards Rome…
斯巴达克斯的死讯回罗马了
with news of Spartacus' death.
现在鬼知道他们在哪儿
Now they could be anywhere.
他们肯定离开城镇到荒野里去了
He would have left the city to rougher terrain.
那样的话很难彻底搜索
It will be no simple task to sweep such an area.
我们需要更多人手
More men would spur to purpose.
我们正在招募士兵 可收获甚微
Attempts to raise soldiers have born shriveled fruit.
都是赛普修斯的错
It is the fault of Seppius.
凡是能舞刀弄枪的他都收走了
He's secured every man familiar with sword as his own.
或许是时候去找他帮忙了
Then perhaps it's time we called in call his support.
他是瓦里留斯的人
He is Varinius' man.
不值得我们这么看得起他
Not worthy of such invitation.
不过我们需要他手下那批人
And yet his men prove a necessity.
如果他们当初在集市上
If we had them in the marketplace,
斯巴达克斯根本不可能近你的身
Spartacus would never have found himself so close to you.
诸神与你作对
The gods conspire against you.
回你的房间去
Return to your quarters.
神明需要虔诚供奉
They demand proper offering…
以血相祭
one of blood and sacrifice.
你是说祭神仪式
You speak of ritual?
重振巴蒂塔斯家
To restore this house…
让我们的敌人跪地求饶
and to force our enemies to their knees.
等到天明 你就去集市
See yourself to market to gather what you require…
需要什么就买什么
when sun greets day.
我们要跟赛普修斯见一面
We shall confer with Seppius.
我来安排
I'll will make arrangement.
你相信诸神会听取你的祷告
You believe the gods will heed your prayers?
只要我祈求正义
If my cause is just.
那就去求他们吧
Then entreat them…
为我指明斯巴达克斯逃往何方
to divine where Spartacus has gone to ground…
以免这个混蛋再取罗马人的性命
before the villain robs another Roman of his life.
提比略 我要射
Tiberius, I would finish.
插我屁股
Place cock in ass.
快点把我衣服拿来
My robes! Quickly!
大家冷静 不要怕
Strike fear and quiet concern.
我们与你们无冤无仇
Our quarrel is not with you.
只与那些以主人自居的人不共戴天
It's with those that would place themselves your master.
主人这个词对我们毫无意义
A title that bears no meaning to us.
如果你们愿意 也不必再与人为奴
Nor to you now, should you wish it so.
你们和我们当初一样
You are presented choice,
面临重大抉择
as we once were.
是要永世臣服于罗马人的暴虐统治
To submit forever to Roman cruelty…
还是揭竿而起为自由而战
or to take up arms and to join us in freedom.
你凭什么给他们提供选择
And who are you, to present such fucking offer?
就凭我是斯巴达克斯
I am Spartacus.
闭上你们的臭嘴
Still your fucking tongues!
你是这里的主人吗
Are you the dominus of this house?
正是
I am.
那我们应该好好谈谈
Then we should have words.
你想要什么
What is it you seek?!
只要你说出来 我就满足你
Give desire voice and see it satisfied!
你应该算个人物吧
You are a man of fucking influence?
没错 我和行政官关系很好
Yes! I have the ear of the Magistrate!
可以替你传话
I can deliver message.
我只对你听到的话感兴趣
It is message sent to you, which I have interest in.
你是巴蒂塔斯的朋友 是不是
You were friend's of Batiatus. Were you not?
是不是
Were you not!?
只是一面之缘
I, I knew him only in passing.
他有很多痴心妄想
He was filled with mad dreams.
比如谋得一官半职
Of rising in prominence of office.
不过他需要支持
Yet he needed support.
所以送出了一件礼物
To gain it he sent a gift.
送到这里的宅子轮流享用
From villa to villa, in this region.
一个女人
A woman.
你知道她
You know of her?
如果我知道 能饶我一命吗
And if I do? My life yet spared?
趁你还有舌头 快说
Speak while you still have fucking tongue.
她…
She was…
她来过这里 她来过这里
She was here! She was here!
为了苟延残喘 你连神仙也敢欺骗
You would break false word to Jupiter himself, just to see another dawn.
黑皮肤 剪得不整齐的短发
Dark of skin. Um hair roughly shorn.
肩膀后有主人家的标记
The mark of her domina upon the back of her shoulder.
她在哪里
Where is she?
我不知道
I do not know!
她后来被拖上马车
She was put to cart after.
后来
After?
我怎么知道她如此重要
How, how could I know that she held meaning?
她没有呼吸吗
Did she not breathe?
她的心不像别的女人那样跳动吗
Did her heart not beat like any other woman's?!
还是你根本没把她当女人看
Yet you did not see a woman, did you?
在你眼里只不过是一个用完不要的奴隶
You just saw something to be used and discarded.
求你…
Please…
一个卑贱的奴隶
You just saw a fucking slave!
看到你的美貌 我勃起了
Your beauty stirs my cock.
勃起了吗 肉眼看不到啊
A rise too slight for eyes to notice.
那人身上好臭
That one smells of shit.
他从哪儿来
From where does he hail?
高卢
Gallia.
难怪呢 高卢人不懂得取悦女人
Gauls. They fuck absent regard of pleasing a woman.
多数男人都这样
A skill lacking in most men.
斯巴达克斯呢
And what of Spartacus?
他的本事怎么样
How does he stand?
他是最厉害的
Above the rest.
无论哪方面
In all regard.
抱歉 我不知道他是你的
Apologies. I did not know he was yours.
我没有这样说过
I do not claim him in such terms.
他也没有这种私心
Nor would he be so enslaved.
他提供保护 以换取你的献身
He offers you protection, in return for affections.
我们没有这种想法
We have no such arrangement.
那就是男女之情了
Is it love then?
明白了 等待爱情的到来
Of course. The hope of love to come.
这可是有危险的
A danger in its own right.
我要看看食物和补给的数量
I need an accounting of all food and supplies.
找维特斯 督促他做完
Find Vitus and see it done.
我们这边没有伤亡
We suffered no casualties.
李斯卡斯和艾克只是皮肉伤
Liscus and Acer took minor wounds.
高卢人越来越嚣张了
The Gauls grow careless.
弄到了多少武器
How many weapons were secured?
再来十几个人也能装备起来
Enough to see a dozen more men well armed.
等我们再攻占一家宅子
And we will put them to use.
就能派上用场了
In the next villa that we take.
主人呢
The dominus?
他想起了一个奴隶
He recalled a slave.
身上的标记与妮维雅相同
Marked the same as Naevia.
她被带到哪里了
Where was she taken?
她被拖上马车
She was put to cart.
送给下一个操蛋的主人享用了
To be passed to the next fucking dominus.
克雷斯
Crixus.
我们会找到她的 兄弟
We will find her, brother.
凡是阻止你们重逢的人
And see everyone that has kept her from your arms…
格杀勿论
to the afterlife.
我去教训他们
I will see to my men.
莱斯克斯需要遮羞布
Rhasko's cock to cover.
下来
Get down.
他只有面包屑
He is given crumbs.
你却送他一顿大餐
Yet you present his fucking meal.
他的心太饥渴了
His heart aches for nourishment.
要好好滋养才行
I would have it well fed.
即使妮维雅活着
Even if Naevia lives,
也不是他记忆中的模样了
she will not be the woman he holds to memory.
如果我们要对抗葛雷博和罗马人
If we are to stand against Glaber and the Romans,
就必须解放能打善斗的人
we must liberate fighting men.
别在无望的目标和无用的家奴身上浪费精力
Not waste effort on dwindling hope and worthless house slaves.
每个人都有自己的价值
Every man has his worth.
罗马人不久就会明白这一点
A lesson the Romans will soon learn.
奴隶身份的束缚已经不存在了
The bonds of slavery have been struck.
你们再也不会感受到那紧紧箍住脖子
Never again will you feel them tighten around your neck,
无法呼吸 生不如死的枷锁
robbing you of breath and life.
希望你们自愿加入我们的行列 为正义而战
See your own join your brothers and take up just cause.
罗马人当我们是狗 任凭他们呼来唤去
We'll see the Romans bleed for taking us as dogs,
我们就要他们付出血的代价
to be yanked by the leash at their command.
泰科斯 索弗斯 发武器
Tychos! Sophus! Weapons!
现在
Now.
谁愿意歃血为盟
Who would have blood?
这个地方
This place.
总感觉黏糊糊的 浑身不自在
The very air clings to the flesh, tainting it.
请闭眼 主人 不要胡思乱想
Close eyes, Domina, and replace thought.
伊莉西娅
Ilithyia.
盖尤斯
Oh, Gaius.
见到你就让人家心神荡漾
You give heart cause to flutter.
我倒是看见水波荡漾了
The water ripples in evidence.
都是肚子里的宝宝闹的
The result of your child.
在我的肚子里大闹天宫呢
And firm kick upon swollen belly.
这么能踢 肯定是男孩
Such aggression prophesies a boy.
我怎么会亏待夫君呢
Would I give you any less?
你最近付出了很多
You have given much of late.
这些我都看在眼里记在心里
Your sacrifice has not gone unnoticed.
不过 我还要你做点事
Yet there is more that I would ask.
只要你开口就行
You need but command it.
天一亮就陪露迪雅去趟集市
Escort Lucretia to market at dawn.
她坚持要举办祭神仪式 净化这里
She intends ceremony to cleanse this house,
指明我的宿敌所在
and deliver my enemies.
我宁愿相信诸神朝罗马撒尿
The gods would rather piss on Rome…
也不相信跟她有联系
than whisper in her ear.
这里的人相信她的预言
People of this city believe her prophet.
不能相信她的话
She is not to be trusted.
不久前你还口口声声说她是你的闺蜜
It was not long ago you named her friend.
那是代价高昂的错误
A mistake dearly paid for.
我们都付出了代价
A sum costing us both.
你真的相信她有诸神庇护
You truly believe her blessed?
如果我们还想重回罗马
Spartacus must fall,
就必须剿灭斯巴达克斯
if we are to be returned to Rome.
不管那女人嘴里喷出的是什么鬼东西
And I am willing to believe whatever revelations…
只要能尽快回到罗马 我都愿意相信
tumble from her lips, if they shall hasten such a day.
现在
Now.
把身子擦干净
See yourself drieded by loving hands,
然后上床吧
and to our bed.
终于又能睡到真正的床了
Oh… to be in a proper bed once more.
好久没享受了
It's been a lifetime.
我从来不知道有这玩意儿
I have never known such a thing.
那就更应该享受了…
Then it is much deserved…
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus…
我们的事情…
what we share…
对你来说有什么意义
what meaning does it hold for you?
你想让我怎么回答你
What answer would you have?
我要听肺腑之言
One spoken from the heart.
我经历过太多的痛苦与悲伤
I have feasted so long on pain and sorrow.
很难回想起幸福的滋味
It is difficult to recall sweeter taste.
除了你依偎在我怀里的时刻
Except when you are in my arms.
那我们永远不要分开
Then let me never be from them.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus…
你已经杀过我一次了
You've already killed me once.
这一次就不要犹豫了
Do not hesitate to revisit the deed.
他跟你无冤无仇 还给了你自由
He did nothing but offer freedom.
你就这么回报他
And this is how you repay?
自由不用他来给
It was not his to grant!
我曾是主人的贴身奴隶
I was body slave to the dominus!
我有地位有尊严
I had position and respect!
你不过是个奴隶
You were a slave.
你拥有的一切全都是转瞬即逝的幻觉
Everything you possessed a mere fleeting illusion.
可你又取代了主人的位置
Do you but take my master's place.
如果你的主人遇到这种情况
And what would your master do now,
又会怎么处置你呢
if he stood so assaulted?
他会杀了我
He would see me dead.
没错
Yes.
他会的
He would.
你真的要训练这混蛋
You yet wish to train this fuck?
应该给这孩子机会
The boy deserves opportunity.
就是因为他有了机会
He was given such a thing,
所以才跑去刺杀你
and made attempt on your life in response.
诸神啊
Gods save me,
我居然同意高卢人的想法
I find myself in agreement with a Gaul.
他满脑子只有奴隶思想
He has known nothing but slavery.
这种思想的束缚并不容易解除
The strength of such a tether not easily severed.
也许永远解除不了
Perhaps never to be so.
那如果我们杀了他呢
And if we take his life?
那些自愿加入我们的人
What message will that send to those…
会有什么样的想法
who wish to join our cause?
- 明智的话就老实点呗 - 那不成了罗马人
- That they had best be agreeable. - We're Romans then?
用恐惧和死亡的威胁统治别人
Commanding through fear and threat of death?
如果他胆敢再袭击人
If he makes attempt again,
我保证让他和他该死的主人团聚
I will make sure he joins his fucking dominus.
那你打算怎么训练这条小疯狗呢
And how do you propose we train this wild little dog?
就跟巴蒂塔斯家的教练训练我一样
As Batiatus had Doctore train me.
那确实训练得好哇
And that turned out so well.
莱比瑞斯抽到了霹雳箭
Liberius draws Plumbatae!
阿多奈克瑟斯抽中了夺魂链
Addonexus selects Vinculum!
放开他
Release him.
我已经赢得了比赛
I stand in victory in my match.
而教练却以鞭抽棒打作为回报
Yet Doctore provides only lash and rod as reward.
你觉得你应该得到别的奖赏吗
You believe you deserve otherwise?
这里是冠军诞生之地 奥诺玛默斯
This is a house of champions, Oenomaus.
不是它服从你
It does not submit to you.
而是你服从它
You submit to it.
明白 主人
Yes, Dominus.
先学会屈膝下跪 以后才能屹立不倒
One must learn to kneel, if he is ever to rise.
这是必修课
A necessary lesson…
如果你想加入巴蒂塔斯家族的冠军之列
if you are to one day join the champions of the House of Batiatus.
我怎么可能成为冠军呢
How is such a thing possible?
答案就在你的心中
The answer lies within your breast!
你拥有不符合年龄的强大力量
You fight with the strength of men beyond your meager years.
但没有经过训练 不能完全发挥出来
Yet lack the discipline to see it properly harnessed.
昆图斯
Quintus.
倒两杯蜂蜜酒
Two cups of mulsum.
告诉我要怎么做
Tell me what I must do.
这是最难的一部分
The most difficult of tasks.
你必须找到自己的目标
You must discover your purpose.
我的目标
My purpose?
你为何而战
That which you fight for.
我为生存而战
I fight to stay alive.
我们都是如此
As do we all.
但要想有超人的成就
But to grasp the heavens…
你就必须找到更伟大的目标
you must fight for something greater.
远比生存重要的东西
Something beyond mere survival.
您是我的主人
You are my dominus.
您一声令下 我就去战斗
I fight for whatever you decide.
不 不
No, no.
无论奴隶还是自由人
This is a decision each man,
都必须独立思考做出决定
whether slave or free born, must forge himself.
全在于你自己
It is yours alone.
为你的目标干杯
To your purpose.
为你未来的命运干杯
And the destiny it shall lead you to.
阿多奈克瑟斯 胜利
Addonexus! Victor!
这也太勉强了
Just fucking barely.
再叫一个人过来打
Send another to face me.
那他的对手该怎么办
And what of his opponent?
一起叫过来
Send him as well.
重复一次
Last position!
进攻
Attack!
左臂别放下去
Keep your left arm up!
进攻
Attack!
盾牌和剑都要灵活使用
You carry a shield as well as sword.
不是对准人 而是肩膀
Not the man, the shoulder.
再来
Again.
进攻
Attack!
很好
Good…
你侧面门户大开
You expose flank.
很多好手都栽在了这里
The ruin of many a great man.
我又不是士兵
I'm no fucking soldier!
暂时不是
Not yet.
第一式和第二式
First and second position.
进攻
Attack!
比我想象的重多了
It's heavier than I imagined.
到时候会变轻的
It will lighten in time.
等到它轻如鸿毛的时候
And when it becomes as a feather?
你觉得它应该飞向哪里呢
What purpose do you think it shall fly to?
这是你自己的选择
One of your own choosing.
- 现在站好了 - 第二式
- Now set foot to path, - And second position!
再来向我进攻
Come at me again.
进攻
Attack!
早该把这小子干掉了
Should have put the boy down.
咬过人的狗 迟早还会露牙齿的
A dog bites once, he will bare fucking teeth again.
真可惜
Pity.
他们为什么盯着我们
Why do they stare?
怎么可能不盯
How could they not?
一位受到诸神庇护的人来到他们身边
When one blessed by the gods moves among them.
诸神
The gods…
对哦
Oh yes.
你以前都不怎么谈论神明
You rarely spoke of them, in times past.
现在说起来倒是像模像样的
Now the divine is held as confidant and council.
今非昔比嘛
Much has changed.
这话有意思
Curious words.
一个自称失忆的人居然这么说
From one who claims no memory of the past.
当曙光来临之时 回忆的影像汇聚成形
Shadows of it begin to form, in the light of a new day.
那是什么形状呢
What shape do they take?
我们俩曾经交换过的一个秘密
One of secrets passed between us.
你说你并不是经常
You confess that you do not always…
听你父亲的命令
heed the commands of your father,
和你丈夫的话
or your husband.
那是我第一次到你们家的时候
You speak of my first visit to your villa.
那时我们还没有真正了解对方
When we had yet to come to truly know one another.
我当时只想讨你开心
I so wished to please you.
你是将军的妻子
You're the wife of the Legatus!
天赐良机
Such a gift.
你不知道当我在家里
You do not know what it means,
再次看到你的时候 我是什么感觉
to find you within the walls of my house once again.
充满了活力和希望
Filling it with life and promise…
在那种暴行中幸存
To survive such barbarity…
你还真是受到诸神庇护的人
you are truly touched by the gods…
多谢
Gratitude.
愿诸神保佑你
May the gods bless you.
伊莉西娅
Ilithyia.
他们似乎被她迷住了
They seem rather taken with her.
赛皮娅 见到你真高兴
Seppia. A welcomed sight.
我哥哥刚动身去找你丈夫会谈
My brother only just departed to sit with your husband.
男人和他们的政治
Men and their politics.
我们别管他们了
Let us leave them to it,
谈谈更要紧的事情吧
and turn thought toward more pressing subject.
罗马最近有什么八卦
What news of latest scandal from Rome!
丈夫和即将出生的孩子
Husband and coming child…
女人有了这两样就不关心八卦了
have drawn attention from such events.
真不敢相信 你居然变了
I cannot believe you so removed!
你几乎和所有人的关系都很好
You are acquainted with positively everybody.
却只有区区几个人想要我
And yet desired by more than a few.
我真嫉妒你当年那么红
How I envy such attentions!
我也很怀念啊
And how I miss them.
有了丈夫 这么多乐子都没有了吗
Must all joy be so abandoned when weighted with husband?
必须如此
It must.
如果女人能正常生育的话
If a woman is of proper breeding.
真可怜
Oh, how miserable.
或许我该乞求神明
Perhaps I should entreat the gods…
避免这种悲惨的命运
to shield me from such dour fate…
愿诸神保佑你
May the gods bless you…
May the Gods bless you…
愿诸神保佑你
May the Gods bless you.
斯巴达克斯曾在你麾下 对吧
Spartacus was one of yours, was he not?
色雷斯那场极其短暂的战事
During your overly brief campaign in Thrace?
召来的炮灰而已
Conscripted to the auxiliary.
那畜生当时就不太听话
An animal prone to disobedience even then.
那畜生是你带到这儿来的
A beast you brought to our shores.
想让他死在竞技场上
To die in the arena.
但他活下来了
Yet he lives.
你的恶趣味害死了我尊贵的堂兄赛克斯
A pleasure denied my noble cousin Sextus.
很多人都蒙受不幸
Many have suffered injury.
斯巴达克斯的死讯必是一剂良药
To be healed by news of Spartacus' fall.
我数月以来殚精竭虑正是为了此事
A venture I eagerly set hands to months past.
我在元老院听说了你的努力 非常感人
Yes word touched me in the Senate of your efforts.
你有多少手下一去不回了
How many of your men has he sent to the afterlife?
那家伙相当狡猾
The man proves resourceful.
他胆敢在集市上攻击你就是明证
As he did when he set upon you in the market square.
很遗憾我的人没有出面解决这一麻烦
It is a pity my men were not present to end the matter.
我曾说过 斯巴达克斯是公敌
Spartacus stands a common foe, as I said.
还是我的护民官抓住了重点
As my tribune cleaves to the heart of it.
斯巴达克斯是我们共同的敌人
Spartacus is enemy to us both,
我们都有血债要他偿还
shared in offense and blood.
所以我们还是抛开分歧
So let us sweep aside differences,
精诚合作 务必要他下跪投降
and in union see him forced to knee.
我需要跟瓦里留斯商量你的提议
I would need to consult Varinius towards such agreement.
你的手下听你的还是听他的
Are they your men, or his?
联手之后由谁主事呢
And who would lead combined effort?
你有剿匪的名分
You shall hold station of note,
但要听我的指挥
second only to my command.
并保证斯巴达克斯伏法之日
And promise that you shall be present…
你一定要到场
when Spartacus is put to grass.
那家伙从你眼皮底下溜走多少次了
The man takes habit of slipping through your fingers.
你究竟哪儿来的信心
What moves you to certainty of victory?
因为这是诸神的意愿
Because the gods themselves will it.
他们正跟你说话 是吧
They speak with you now do they?
借这家宅院的旧主人之口
Through voice of former domina of this very house.
露迪雅吗
Lucretia?
诸神保佑她
They have blessed her,
她在大屠杀那晚有了诸神的指引
as they blessed her the night they guided her…
才能侥幸活下来
from death in the massacre.
但她并非仅有的幸运儿
Yet she is not alone in such fortune.
难道不是诸神指引
Did the gods not guide…
你妻子才能平安无事吗
your wife to safety as well?
伊莉西娅在那之前就离开了
Ilithyia took leave before unfortunate turn.
随行的还有你的一帮手下
And with her a clutch of your men.
那些士兵本来可以扭转乾坤
Soldiers that might have tipped the balance…
阻止斯巴达克斯的恐怖大屠杀
towards halting Spartacus short of fucking slaughter.
你在我面前讲话最好客气点 小子
You will tend your words with more care in my presence, boy.
别这样 大家坐下来…
Come, let us take seat…
我已经很注意措辞了
My words are carefully chosen.
对一个只能靠岳父上位的软蛋
For a man holding title as favor to his wife's father.
你要是胆敢再这样说话
You speak to me in such manner again…
你的舌头我要定了
and I will have your tongue.
可要不走我的手下
Yet not my men.
老屌怒胀
My cock rages on!
干倒你爹 日翻你娘
I put you down, I give you shit.
没事撒尿在你坟头上
I piss on your grave for the sport of it.
老子好爽
Expect no less.
老屌怒胀
My cock rages on!
过来
You.
奴隶 给我打满酒
Slave, see my jug filled.
莱斯克斯
Rhaskos.
自个儿去拿酒
Fetch drink yourself.
打酒回来前可别偷喝 奴隶
Do not fucking drink jug before return, slave!
你太给他们面子了 他们还没那个资格
You offer privilege before it is properly earned.
难道你想要他们卑躬屈膝 低声下气
And you would have them bow and scrape in service,
就像以前伺候主子那样吗
as they did before their dominus?
不 但我绝不会平等对待他们
No. Yet neither would I have them seen as equal.
他们不像我们 还不是真正的兄弟
They were not forged at the brotherhood, as we were.
他们是自愿加进来的
They join our cause of their own free will.
这样的火燃烧起来更加猛烈
Such fire may yet prove more fierce.
或是在狂风暴雨中熄灭
Or be extinguished by threatening storm.
天一亮我就行动
I would move at first light.
还有很多宅子要去
There are yet more villas.
见到宝贝啦
You press fortune.
死死地盯着我们的屠影英雄
Glaring so at the slayer of Theokoles.
他的胜利只是证明了强者也会败
His victory but proving even giants fall.
你叫什么名字 小个子
What name do you go by, little man?
我好在你死的时候哀悼
So I may properly mourn your passing?
我叫提比略
I am called Tiberius.
提比略
Tiberius!?!
你这么黑 怎么有个罗马名字
You are far too dark to have such a fair Roman name.
我的罗马血统多过叙利亚
I am more Roman than Syrian.
我们训练场也曾有个叙利亚人
There was a Syrian at our ludus.
那混蛋相当奸诈 不知他是死是活
A treacherous fuck, if ever there breathed.
你那里还有家人吗
You had family there?
我只记得有个兄弟
I only recall a brother.
我也有过兄弟
I too had a brother.
不在了吗
No longer?
被罗马人杀死了
He was struck down by the Romans.
是你们起兵反叛的时候吗
When you turned swords against them?
总有一天你也会的
As you shall one day.
只要你还有一点点理智
If you hold any fucking sense.
看着我
Look at me…
我射的时候要看着漂亮的脸蛋
I would see that pretty face as I burst…
你这该死的畜生
You fucking animal!
米拉
Mira…
滚
Go!
不然我阉了你
Or part with your cock.
如果你不是斯巴达克斯的婊子
If you were not Spartacus' bitch,
我就教教你怎么用这把刀
I would show you how to use that.
还有我的老屌
And my cock.
抱歉
Apologies.
- 我会看好莱斯克斯 - 我是自愿找上他的
- I will see that Rhaskos - I chose to lay with a fucking Gaul.
为什么
Why?
不是谁都能有斯巴达克斯暖床
Not all of us have Spartacus to warm our beds,
拿正眼瞧我们
and see us to position.
你有了自由 还甘愿受这人渣奴役
You gain freedom only to be enslaved by that shit?
自由不是白来的
Freedom is not without cost.
我拿仅有的本钱去换
I pay with the only coin I have.
你也一样
As do you.
也许我们该站远点
Perhaps we should stand further away.
以免诸神的雷电打偏了地方
For fear of errant bolt from the heavens.
这仪式说不定有收获 反正不花钱
Such ritual may bring profit, absent cost.
那头羊可价值不菲
The goat came at no small expense.
诸神向我诉说欺骗与背叛
The gods whisper of deceit and treachery.
并保证无论何人对你有所欺瞒
And give assurance that those who would harbor secrets against you…
必将公之于众
shall be brought to light.
请接受我们的祭品
Accept our offering,
蒙您恩赐 剿杀残敌
and bless us with your favor against our enemies…
这么做明智吗
Is it wise?
让这个疯女人拿着刀子
To allow such unsteady hands to play with knives?
住嘴
Hold tongue.
你心愿已了
Your will now ends.
要不再来一头羊
Perhaps another goat…?
仪式结束后
When ritual is ended,
清干净血污 照看好露迪雅
see blood cleansed and Lucretia attended.
你接下来要对战卡拉塔克斯
You are to fight Caratacus next.
一头杀人无数的野兽
A beast that has claimed many lives.
你认为他能杀掉我
You believe he shall end mine?
就你这身体状况
In your condition?
如果他做不到
If he does not…
派有本事的人来
send one that will.
你已经迈出了
You have taken important step…
脱离低劣野兽的重要一步
towards rising above base animal.
在那种地方战斗 我感到羞耻
It shames me I fought in that place.
毫无荣誉可言
Absent thoughts of honor.
生活毫无意义
The pits are for men…
只能受辱等死的人才会去地下角斗场
whose lives promise nothing greater than an ugly end.
你注定要追寻更崇高的命运
You are destined for far grander fate.
竞技场
The arena.
传奇辈出之地
A place where legends are forged.
真替那些敢在沙场挑战你的人感到战栗
I fear for those that dare take the sands against you.
我一定让他们死得其所
I shall make their deaths memorable.
诸神会很高兴的
The gods will be pleased.
我不为诸神而战
I do not fight for the gods.
我为你而战
I fight for you.
这是我的目标 我的生命
That is my purpose. My life.
为巴蒂塔斯家族争光
To honor the House of Batiatus.
这是我的荣幸
The honor is mine.
好样的
Yeah!
是你
You.
主人
Domina!
有人拜访
Men approach!
有火把
Torches!
是从北边过来的
Arriving from the north!
多少人
How many?
六个 也许更多
Six. Maybe more.
集合所有男人
Gather the men…
等等 他们可能是大部队的斥候
Wait. These may be scouts from a larger force.
只要有一人逃出我们的掌心
If a single rider was to escape our grasp,
必将后患无穷
he could bring a far greater concern.
那就不给他们逃的机会
Then we shall grip tightly.
有个更好的办法
There is a better way.
能让罗马人察觉不到我们的行踪
One that will keep our movements yet hidden from the Romans…
我奉赛普修斯的命令
I would have words with your dominus,
要和你的主人谈谈
on orders of Seppius.
抱歉
Apologies.
他去派肯蒂亚谈生意了
Business has called him to Picentia.
派肯蒂亚 没听说过他喜欢那地方
Picentia? I have never known him to favor the city.
他不喜欢
He does not.
他喜欢的是城里的妓女
He favors its whores.
你是他的贴身奴隶吧
You are his body slave, are you not?
我叫提比略
Tiberius.
提比略
告诉我 为什么没和主人同去
Tell me, why are you not at your dominus' side?
因为他信不过别人
Because there's no one he trusts more,
在他享受床笫之欢时 帮他照看宅子
to see his villa attended while his cock is satisfied.
你倒是尽忠尽职
You serve your master well.
回你的岗位去吧
Return to your charge.
且慢
Wait!
你们自卡普亚远道而来
You have come a fair distance from Capua.
进来吧 我给你们点东西
Come, and I will give you something…
保证不虚此行
to make effort worthwhile…
他背叛我们
He betrays us.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
你为什么不让他们走
Why did you stop them from leaving?
他杀了那个人
He killed the man…
他是看到了那些人毫无胜算
When he saw they would not win.
他注意到了我的脖子
His eyes fell to my neck!
他看到我的项圈没了
He saw the absence of my collar!
如果我就这么让他走
If I had not allowed him in,
他肯定会带更多人来
he would have returned with more men!
你做的很好 提比略
You did well, Tiberius.
纳西尔
Nasir.
我兄弟管我叫纳西尔
My brother called me Nasir.
是谁深更半夜前来打扰
Who disturbs peace at such an hour?
我是带着礼物来的
I come bearing a gift…
这礼物能助你铲除斯巴达克斯
which shall set you upon path to the fall of Spartacus.
诸神果真听到我的祈祷了
The gods truly heed my prayers.